Hello, I'm Kilian, famous literary historian.
You all know the true story of a successful man, who, on Christmas Eve, with the help of three spirits
becomes a total loser.
But did you know that author Charles Dickens had a twin named Gary Dickens,
who edited Charles' stories to reach a more
niche audience.
Including an edition of Oliver Twist
with the children edited out.
Gary's most famous book is Carol Christmas A,
about a man named Ebenezer Jennrouge.
Unlike Ebenezer Scrooge, who is a greedy man
you eventually force old English actors to play,
Ebenezer Jennrouge was the nicest, most generous, benevolent, altruistic,
and all the other synonyms I could find on Thesaurus.
I have illegally downloaded this book and updated it
for 2019, without the approval of the Dickens estate. Sue me Gary!
*fake coughs three times*
Marley was dead.
Dead as a surprised organization in Denmark, that much is true. Did Jennrouge know he was dead? Of course he did.
He was his wife's headmaster for many years.
It was a colorful and pretty warm Christmas Eve.
It's not the 1800s anymore. Christmas these days has bathing weather.
Ebenezer was the head teacher of Poor Inner-City Poverty School.
And all the students and parents loved him.
The old man sat busy in his principal's office.
When his nephew walked in.
"Good day, uncle!"
"Merry Christmas, nephew. How is your sex life?"
"What!?"
"Why are you not married and have started a family?"
"Busy, I guess."
"May I join you for Christmas?"
"No uncle. Not celebrating it."
I'm too busy with homework from Cambridge Oxford Business School."
"BAH!"
"Humbug. You should celebrate Christmas! It's about family!"
"No, uncle! I wanna live in a penthouse!"
"Good afternoon!
"Merry Christmas!"
"And a good evening!"
"MERRY CHRISTMAS!"
The second he left, two gentlemen enter the office.
"Hello, sir. We are collecting money for..."
"Uuhhh..."
"Surfboard Santa Orphanage."
"I shall ignore your trespassing, and give you...
He whispered in his ear.
"Lord bless me! Are you serious!?"
"Not a farthing less!"
"Well, now I feel bad for scamming you!"
"Hey, scammers need to eat!"
Ebenezer went back to work, and after a while someone knocked on his door.
It was one of his teachers, Bob Cratchit.
"Sir, can I come to work tomorrow, correcting tests?"
"Working on Christmas, Mr. Cratchit?"
"Preposterous!"
"I get really bored, an-and I don't celebrate Christmas, because you know... Jewish."
"I would be happy if someone told me I could take the day off to celebrate the birthday of the King of England!"
"Why can't YOU take the day off to celebrate the birthday of the King of the Jews!?"
"It's a poor excuse not to pick the state's pockets every December 25th!"
"Okay, a couple of problems with that statement, but I don't think I can change your mind, so I'll go."
"Merry Christmas!"
"Uh, happy holidays, sir."
At the end of the day,
Jennrouge went back to his super small house in the middle of nowhere, because that's all he could afford.
He sat down to not work, because he was gonna take a break until a couple of days after New Year.
After a couple of hours, he got up to make some coffee.
NOT tea, COFFEE! We break stereotypes on this channel.
He noticed the chair had moved to the other side. Could there be a ghost here?
Of course there should be a ghost. It was the only explanation. He really believed in ghosts.
It was the ghost of his former deputy headmaster, Jacob Marley.
" What do you want with me? I'll give you anything!"
"I know you always give everything to everyone!"
"Dreadful apparition! Why do you trouble me?"
"And what's with the expensive suit? Are-are those Porsche car keys?"
"I always gave my everything to everyone, never myself."
"Now, I am forced to live in an eternal midlife chrisis."
"You can escape my fate."
"Tonight, you will be visited by three spirits."
"I'll have to bake something for them."
"No! Stop it! Bye."
When the digital alarm struck 1:00, the spirit casually walked through the front door.
"Are you the spirit, sir? Whose coming was foretold to me?"
"Yes, hello. I'm Dr. Ghost of Christmas Past,"
"Not a medicine doctor. I'm a doctor in physics, which is why I can time-travel."
"Let's go."
The house dissappeared around him.
It was clear, hot and sandy on the ground.
"I... I was a boy here. This is Wales."
Uuhhh, literary trivia: Gary had never been to Wales.
"How is this possible?"
"Aww, You think this vision is to teach you general relativity?"
"No! Focus!"
"This is your old school."
"Yes, I'm in there, alone, watching a Christmas movie."
"You sure?"
"No... I'm watching Wall Street."
"Yes, you were quite awesome as a young boy."
Jennrouge got to see Christmas' pass, the room decaying,
And him, always alone, watching kick-ass greed movies.
A moment later, he was back in a small business in London.
"Do you recognize this man?"
"Arnold Fezziwig."
"What, no."
"Fezziwig is not a real surname. Time travel has scrambled your brain."
"I used to work here."
"But you are not here."
"Yes, because I refused to work on Christmas."
"And thus, you never got stock options."
They moved again. Ebenezer, now older, and the young woman sitting next to him.
"I don't care about being poor!"
I'm finding myself right now."
"You're like 35. It's getting irresponsible!"
"Ah, Belle. She was so beautiful."
"Then you got married."
"Yes."
"And the bedroom was completely dead."
"Spirit! Why do you delight to torture me?"
"Except on Christmas Day, and that's why you love it."
"Spirit! Leave me! Take me back! Haunt me no longer!"
He woke up, mid snore in a pitch-black room.
Then his digital clock struck 2:00.
"JennROOOOOOOOOOOOOOOUUUUUUUUUUUGGGGGGGEE!"
"Get your arse over here!"
It was a good thing he did not rent an apartment, because he would get evicted.
There was a giant man standing in his kitchen.
"I am the Ghost of the Next 22 Hours."
"Now touch me!"
Ebenezer did not like where this was going, but uh, can't disobey THIS dude.
They moved to the exact same spot, but it was daytime.
"When are we?"
"This is Christmas Morning."
"Then, where are my presents?"
"Out there, in the mailbox."
Hundreds upon hundreds of Christmas cards.
"But I wanted a toaster!"
"If you had been a greedy, rich man, you would have gotten lots of physical gifts from people trying to impress you.
"Go humbug yourself!"
"There is more to life than materialistic things!"
"Okay?"
The two traveled to a house Ebenezer did not recognize.
"This is the house of Bob Cratchit and family."
"Are they microwaving pizzas on Christmas!?"
"They were gonna have a nice kosher dinner,"
"but because Bob didn't get to work, they didn't have enough food, and are eating frozen pizzas."
"Forced to pick away the ham."
"The youngest Cratchit boy could barely walk. Use your imagination.
"What's wrong with the boy?"
"Tiny Tim is dying."
"I will pay for his medical expenses."
"We're-we're in modern, England, You-you don't have to-"
"I WILL save this boy!"
"A-alright."
They teleported to his nephew's Christmas study group, overhearing their conversation.
"He's poor, in debt, and even if he had money, he would give it away! My uncle owns nothing he likes!"
"Wow, my nephew is a prick!"
"But what he's saying is true."
"He's always wanted to visit Cancun,"
"But he never will!"
"He speaks the truth once again."
"Because of your decisions, you will never meet a Mexican."
"I don't care about their gay mockery on my behalf!"
"I-I don't think that means the same thing."
"I know I helped people!"
"Like, wh-what year are you in? I mean-"
"OH! You helped people did you?"
They moved again, and saw people without access to showers.
"What's the problem with them?"
"Those are your former students, because you believed in them,"
"They set the bar too high, and when they failed, they turned to opium."
"No!"
"Oh man, look down here! Look at these young adults!"
"Who-who are they?"
"They are your young adults! the WORLD'S young adults!"
"Who sit at home and watch YouTube videos instead of getting a low-paying job at Starbucks!"
"NO!"
"Get them away from me!"
"Okay, I'm gone."
The spirit was gone, but Jenn Rouge remembered Marley's prediction.
And now the final ghost approached.
"Are you the final spirit? Ghost of-I mean, Dr. Ghost of Christmas Yet to Come?
Ebenezer was moved to a funeral that lots of people attended.
"Is this my funeral? Wow, so many people will remember me."
"Who cares about how many people missed your brain!? You're dead!
"*sighs* How did I die, spirit?"
"So what?"
"Paying for Tim's medical expenses made you broke, so you had to sell everything!"
"And you sold one of the items stolen from the antique roadshow!"
"And evaluation gave you a heart attack!"
"Argh! At-at least Tiny Tim?"
"Oh, he died."
"Please, spirit! Did-did he at least get to meet an Avenger?"
"Yeah, Hawkeye."
"NOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOO!!!!!!!"
"Jeremy Renner showed up, and signed for 'em!"
"NOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOO!!!!!!!!!!!!!"
"Please, tell me I can change! I will disrespect Christmas!"
"Please spare me!"
He collapsed and dwindled by a bedpost.
"Y-yes! I'm alive!"
"A Merry Christmas to NO-ONE!"
"I have to change my life!"
"I have to tweet something racist so I get fired from my head-whatever job!"
After that, he ran out, ruining the day of every person he met.
"My dear sir!"
"Oi, Mr. Jennrouge!"
"The check will bounce and shove those orphans up your rectum!"
He made his way to Bob's house.
"Bobby, I'm out. I'm starting a company in the military-industrial complex!"
"O-okay."
"Oi, Tiny Tim!"
"Yes, sir!"
"Ask for Joaquin Phoenix. Bye, losers!"
Jennrouge was better than his word. He became just the worst person, focused on power.
If he was a flavor, you bet he would be sour.
Truth is, he didn't even meet spirits.
Because he was nice, he decided to give a gas repair company with a bad review a chance.
Yes, it was all a gas leak, but the lesson remains the same.
But you are still welcome to re-watch this every year. God Jul (Merry Christmas), and that is the Kilian Christmas Carol.
And now our sponsor.
This video is sponsored by NordVPN.
You know who doesn't care about privacy? Santa.
He tracks your IP to see if you've been naughty online.
But he can't with NordVPNs double data encryption.
Click the link in the top of the description and use code 'kilianexperience' to save 81 percent, and get four extra months of NordVPN and Nord Pass for free.
If you're a subscriber of mine, NordVPNs military-grade encryption is the only thing that's gonna save you from Santa's wrath.
Click the link in the top of the description. I hope you enjoyed the video, please like and comment if you did.